Guide to the Whitman College Sports Studies, Recreation and Athletics Records 1886-2003
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Whitman College Sports Studies, Recreation and Athletics Records
1886-2003
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Whitman College
WCA.081
35 linear feet 21 cartons, 21 manuscript boxes, 6 binders
Materials related to Whitman College varsity athletics, sports and athletic classes, and intramural sports.
Collection is open for research.
A Whitman College Athletics Association formed in 1886, due in part to a desire of students to participate in baseball. The first football team was formed in 1892. Women's basketball was being played as early as 1897, and tennis was a popular early activity. The arrival in 1906 of Raymond Vincent Borleske was a seminal moment in the development of Whitman athletic programs. Borleske was considered the greatest football running back in the West during his playing days. Borleske graduated in 1910 and returned in 1915 to teach and coach, becoming the dominant figure in Whitman athletics until 1947.
Whitman College was one of the original members of the Pacific Northwest Intercollegiate Athletic Conference (PNIAC), which, at the time of its conception in 1910, contained schools such as the University of Washington, University of Oregon, and Washington State College, later Washington State University. In later years, most of the larger schools withdrew, leaving Whitman, College of Puget Sound, Linfield College, and Pacific University, all of which belong to the present-day Northwest Conference. Willamette University, Pacific Lutheran University, George Fox College, Lewis and Clark College and Whitworth University have since joined the conference, leaving its present membership at nine institutions.
Whitman dropped football in 1977, but still competes in intercollegiate cross country, tennis, volleyball, swimming, golf, basketball, and baseball, as well as maintaining an active intramural program. Nationally, Whitman was originally a member of the National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics (NAIA) and is currently a member of the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division III.
The Whitman College Sports Studies, Recreation and Athletic Records consist of news clippings, photographs, calendars, schedules, publications, correspondence, and memos pertaining to sports of all levels at Whitman College. It also contains information on the construction and maintenance of the Walla Walla Stadium, built in 1925 and renamed Borleske Stadium in 1940.
Borleske, Raymond Vincent
College athletes--Washington (State)
- Administrative Subject File, 1
  This section consists of reports, policies, and correspondence between Whitman College and various governing bodies; NAIA, PNIAC, NCAA and Northwest Conference.
  - Borleske stadium board minutes and info, 1990-2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Athletics: Pacific Northwest Intercollegiate Athletic Conference, 1951-1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Athletics: Pacific Northwest Intercollegiate Athletic Conference, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Athletics: Pacific Northwest Intercollegiate Athletic Conference, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Athletics: Pacific Northwest Intercollegiate Athletic Conference, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Robert Thomsen Correspondence, 1946-1962 (Box 3)
    Coaches association Pacific NW Conference 1946-1950; correspondence between football coaches, 1962; coaches association minutes, 1962.
  - Physical Education at Whitman College: Studies, 1968-1978 (Box 4)
    binder of PE discussion material, 1978; packet of write-up on the state of physical education at Whitman, 1968.
  - Report on Athletics and Scholarship at Whitman College, 1928-1974 (Box 5)
    NCWSA regulations for the rewarding of financial aid to student athletes, 1974; study of athletics and scholarship at Whitman College, 1928.
  - Pacific Northwest Intercollegiate Athletic Association, 1970-1989 (Box 6)
    correspondence, 1970's; PNIAC guide from the 1980's; Agreement 1976.
  - Miscellaneous information of NAIA-NCAA, 1970-1979 (Box 7)
    Correspondence, minutes of committee meeting.
  - Intramural Sports, 1906-1979 (Box 8)
    Women's athletic association of Whitman College; scheduling of athletic events 1970's; correspondence with University of Montana and University of Washington, 1906; Intramural sports constitutions, 1930's-1940's
  - Athletics miscellaneous, 1949-1977 (Box 9)
    articles, flyers, review 1977, correspondence, schedules, folder of 'general' with discussions about dropping football 1949-1974, clippings about football, bicycling proposal, suggestions for careers, and ski championships.
  - Administrative materials, 1970-1999 (Box 14)
    NAIA Administrative Manuals, guides and handbooks (1980's and 1990's) Women's sports 1980-1981 correspondence NAIA District One material 1983-1984 NAIA District One procedures and statistics, 1970's Football correspondence, 1970's
  - Borleske stadium athletic complex and board, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borleske stadium board minutes, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Policy manual for Borleske stadium, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Borleske stadium board minutes and info, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Borleske stadium board minutes, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Borleske stadium board minutes, 1972-1985 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Report on Studies for Rehabilitation of Borleske Stadium, Walla Walla, WA, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Loose papers re: Borleske stadium, 1926-1980 (bulk 1960s) (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - ORB architects plan for Veteran's Memorial Park, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Borleske stadium history, 1926-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Borleske trophy award list, 1937-1994 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Stadium board minutes and documents, 1964-1973 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Stadium board minutes and documents, 1973-1981 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Stadium board minutes and documents, 1976-1978 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Stadium board minutes and documents, 1978-1981 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Stadium board minutes and documents, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Public disclosure documents, stadium board, 1975-2001 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Athletic eligibility forms, Undated (Box 25)
  - PNIAC and NAIA documents, 1903-1976 (Box 31, Box 32)
    "The Early Years of PNIAC" by L.J. Sparks, 1925; PNIAC Agreements, 1903-1972; Correspondences and miscellaneous items, 1947-1976; Participation lists, 1953-1972; PNIAC new conference agreement, 1961-1963; documents re: enlargement of the Conference, 1964-1965; Linfield College case documents, 1967-1968; PNIAC article by Robert Whitner and Louis Perry, 1965; Athletic schedules, 1952-1974; NAIA Documents, 1955-1971; NAIA minutes, 1954-1972; PNIAC Eligibility Certificates, 1955-1972.
  - Publicity relating to athletics, 1940-1942 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Sports clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - NAIA newsletter, 1965-1967 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - News releases, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - News releases, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - NAIA District #1 newsletter, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - news clippings sports general, 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - News releases, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - News releases, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - NAIA District 1 newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - NWC newsletter, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - NAIA news releases, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - NAIA Official Records Book, 1977-1980 (Box 16)
  - NAIA District 1 newsletter, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - NWC Newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - NAIA national newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - NAIA District 1 newsletter, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - NAIA News, official magazine of the NAIA (Incomplete), 1979-1982 (Box 16)
  - Sports clippings, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - NWC newsletter, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - NAIA newsletter, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - News releases from other institutions, Undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - NCAA PR manual, Undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "Northwest conference", Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - NWC all-conference awards, Undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Various pamphlets from collegiate athletic organizations, Undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 2
  - Raymond V. Borleske "Giant" file, 1927-1937 (Object 1)
  - Raymond V. Borleske "Giant" file, 1930-1932 (Object 2)
  - Raymond V. Borleske "Giant" file, 1933-1936 (Object 3)
  - Raymond V. Borleske "Giant" file, 1936-1939 (Object 4)
  - Raymond V. Borleske "Giant" file, 1937-1941 (Object 5)
  - Coach Joe Beidler files, 1952-1955 (Object 6)
- Athletics subject files, 3
  Files pertaining to individual sports at Whitman College organized first chronologically and then by discipline. The bulk of the material covers the 1960's through the 1980's.
  - Record book of athletes (all sports), 1886-1947 (Box 15b)
  - Expense journal, 1915-1922 (Box 10b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1909 (Box 10c)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1911 (Box 10c)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1915-1916 (Box 10b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1917-1920 (Box 10b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1921-1922 (Box 10b)
  - Baseball scorebook (intramural), 1923-1924 (Box 15a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1923-1924 (Box 10a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1925-1929 (Box 10b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1931-1932 (Box 10c)
  - Baseball scorebooks, 1930, 1933 (Box 10d)
  - Baseball scorebooks, 1934-1935 (Box 10c)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1936-1937 (Box 10b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1938-1939 (Box 10c)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1916-1917 (Box 10b)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1918-1919 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1926 (Box 10d)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1926-1927 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1927-1928 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1928 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1928-1929 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1929-1930 (Box 10d)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1930-1931 (Box 10d)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1931-1932 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1932-1933 (Box 10a)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1933-1934 (Box 10c)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1934-1935 (Box 10c)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1936-1939 (Box 10d)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1938-1939 (Box 15b)
  - Tri-State Interscholastic Track Meet, 1908-1910 (Box 30)
  - Track meet program, Whitman College v. University of Idaho, 1913 May 24 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Football programs, 1912, 1920-1929 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1940 (Box 15a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1941 (Box 15b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1941-1942 (Box 10a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1943 (Box 10a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1944 (Box 15a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1945 (Box 15b)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1939-1940 (Box 15b)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1941-1942 (Box 15b)
  - Basketball scorebook, 1943-1946 (Box 15a)
  - Basketball programs, 1950-1959 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Basketball, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Basketball press guides, 1948-1970 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Football roster, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Football programs, 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Football programs, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Football programs, 1950-1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Football scorebook, 1956-1960 (Box 15a)
  - Football, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Conference track and field meet program, 1942 May 22 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Spring sports rosters (includes baseball and tennis), 1947 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Spring sports rosters, 1950-1959 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Football, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Football, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Football, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "Meet the Missionaries" program, 1963-1968 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Football, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Football, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Football, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Football and cross country press guides, 1960-1969 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Football programs, 1960-1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Football, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Football, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Football, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Football, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Football, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Football, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Football, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Football, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Football, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Football, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Football NAIA releases, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Football releases NWC, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Football history at Whitman College, Undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Football controversy/cancellation, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Football misc., Undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Football programs, 1970-1979 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Whitman football news clippings, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 9, Folder 10)
  - Whitman football articles re cancellation of program, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cross-country meets, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Cross-country, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Cross-country, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cross-country, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Soccer, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Soccer, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Women's soccer, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Soccer, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Women's soccer, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Soccer, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Fall sports press books, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Basketball, 1960-1969 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - WC Basketball, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Basketball statistics, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Basketball rosters, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Basketball District #1 NAIA, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Basketball, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Basketball statistics, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - WC Basketball, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - WC Sports releases, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Sports correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Basketball season records, 1960-1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Basketball scorebooks, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Whitman basketball, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Basketball newsclippings, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Basketball misc., circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Basketball, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Basketball news releases, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Wrestling, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Wrestling, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Wrestling, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Wrestling, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Wrestling, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Wrestling, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Wrestling, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Wrestling, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Women's basketball, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Basketball programs, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Volleyball, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Winter sports, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Winter-spring sports, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Winter sports, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Winter sports, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Swimming, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Wrestling, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Baseball scorebooks, 1963 (Box 15b)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1967 (Box 15a)
  - Baseball scorebook, 1972 (Box 15a)
  - Track, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Tennis, 1976-1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Baseball, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Golf, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Track, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Golf, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Baseball, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Spring sports, circa 1960s (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Spring sports, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Martin Invitational track meet clippings, circa 1950s-1980 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Spring sports, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Spring sports, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Spring sports, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Spring sports, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Spring sports, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Spring sports, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Spring sports, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Spring sports, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Spring sports, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Spring sports, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Spring sports, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Spring sports, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Spring sports, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Tennis, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Track, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Spring sports, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Baseball, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Baseball, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cross country, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Cross country, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Lacrosse, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Women's soccer, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Men's soccer, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Women's soccer, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Men's soccer, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Whitman cross country, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Basketball rosters, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Whitman basketball, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Whitman women's basketball, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ski team, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Skiing miscellaneous, Undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Women's volleyball, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Women's basketball, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Volleyball, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Swimming, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Women's basketball, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Basketball statistics, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Basketball, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Basketball releases, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Basketball clippings, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Basketball miscellaneous, Undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Basketball, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Basketball, circa 1990s (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Rugby, circa 1990s (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Winter sports, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Golf, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Baseball, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Tennis, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Track, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Men's tennis, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Track, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Golf, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Tennis, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Baseball, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Track, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Tennis, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Baseball, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Golf, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 51)
- General athletic information; sports teams, awards, memorabilia, 4
  - Men's and women's rugby articles, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12, Folder 13)
  - Whitman rugby: Motherruckers calendars; Reaper Madness, 1991-1992; 2001-2008 (Box 22)
  - Whitman lifeguard training, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Whitman women's soccer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Whitman ski team, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Whitman tennis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Whitman volleyball, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21, Folder 22)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Whitman sports clips, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Whitman sports clips, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Whitman sports clips, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Whitman athletics hall of fame, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Royal F. Niles trophy, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - History of football and other sports at Whitman, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Coach and Athlete article on Whitman College, 1959 May (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Coaches portraits, circa 1960s, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Paul Bunyan axe - Willamette/Whitman trophy history, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Borleske trophy winners, 1936-1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Miller sports awards, Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Whitman "Shockers" name change idea, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - R.V. Borleske clippings, Undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Athletics, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Borleske awards, Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Awards banquets, circa 1930-circa 1960 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Awards banquet, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Cosida digest- College sports information directors newsletters, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Borleske memorial foundation and stadium, Undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Klise Memorial track award, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Athletic committee reports, circa 1948 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Athletic budget, circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Physical education at Whitman College, report by Edward W. Malan, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Intramural athletics, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Registration forms for Big Onion marathon, 1980 October (Box 18, Folder 28)
- Whitman College sports photographs, Undated; 5 (Box 23)
- Accession 2018-004, circa 1900-1990; 34; 0.5 linear feet 1 box. (Box 34)
  This is an unprocessed addition to the Whitman College Sports Studies, Recreation, and Athletics collection, consisting of materials collected by Whitman College Athletic Director Dean Snider, from alumni who dropped them off during various athletic reunions. Materials include photographs, newspaper clippings, magazines, and other such ephemera from Whitman College football, cross country, and golf teams, as well as a basketball pamphlet, and a Walla Walla Sweets baseball photo.
- Accession 2019-026, 1978-2011; 12 linear feet 15 boxes (Box 35-52)
  This is an unprocessed accession that contains subject files and photographs, including CDs, relating to the following Whitman College sports: basketball, soccer, volleyball, tennis, golf, swimming, rugby, baseball, and cross country. The records date from approximately 1978 to 2011.